https://komennyc.org/privacy-policy/

You are here: Home
»
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
The Greater New York City Affiliate of Susan G. Komen for the Cure (“Komen” or “we” or “us” or “our”) is committed to responsible information handling practices. You can visit most pages on the Sites without giving us any information about yourself, but sometimes we need information to provide information or services that you request. This Privacy Policy explains data collection and use in those situations.
By visiting the Sites, you consent to the information practices described in this Privacy Policy.
This Privacy Policy applies to the following sites: https://komennyc.org
(and each sub-domain associated with this URL) and other websites operated by or for Komen (collectively, the “Sites”). This Privacy Policy does not apply to other sites that may be accessible through the Sites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of persons or entities that Komen does not control, manage or employ.
The Sites contain links to other sites that are operated by third parties, including, but not limited to, third party sites that may display the name, trademarks, service marks and logos of Komen.
We encourage you to read the privacy policies of those other sites to learn how they collect and use information about you.
In order to fully understand your rights, we encourage you to read this Privacy Policy.
Komen reserves the right at any time and without notice to change this Privacy Policy simply by posting such changes on the Sites.
Any such change will be effective immediately upon posting.
To assist you with reading through our Privacy Policy, we have provided answers to questions that you may find most important:
What type of information does Komen COLLECT and how is the information USED?
Does Komen use COOKIES, OTHER TECHNOLOGIES or THIRD PARTIES to INDIRECTLY collect information on the Sites?
Does Komen SHARE the information that I have provided or that has been collected?
Do I have CHOICES regarding how my Personal Information is used?
How can I UPDATE or CHANGE my information?
How does Komen SECURE my personal information?
Does Komen collect information from CHILDREN?
If I give Komen the name and email address of my family or friends, how is that information used?
Whom can I CONTACT if I have questions or concerns about the Privacy Policy?
Will this Privacy Policy CHANGE?
What constitutes my acceptance of this Privacy Policy?
How does Komen protect the information that I may provide by telephone or regular mail or in person?
Where can I get more information about the Privacy Policy?
What type of information does Komen COLLECT and how is the information USED?
While you are visiting the Sites, Komen may collect two types of information about users:
“Personal Information” (such as name, email address, mailing address, phone, credit card or debit card, personal preferences and other account-related information) and “Aggregate Information” (such as information about how many users log on to the Sites on a daily basis).
Personal Information is collected online when you voluntarily submit non-public personal information on the Sites by requesting information, purchasing our products, signing up for an account or other Services, receiving electronic notices or other similar communications and other similar activities.
Aggregate Information is non-personally identifiable/anonymous information about you, such as pages most frequently accessed by you, time spent on a page or area of the Sites, the number of visits to the Sites by you, types of browser used by you, cookie preferences or search terms entered by you.
Aggregate Information is used in a collective manner, and no single person can be identified by that compiled information (for example, the number of people who logged into the Sites in a particular day).
Aggregate Information does not personally identify a specific user.
Personal Information That You Provide to Us
We may obtain Personal Information about you ONLY if you elect to give us that information. Types of Personal Information may include the following:
Name
Address
Zip code
Telephone number
Occupation
E-mail address
Credit card number and expiration date (for online purchases or donations)
Name of organization (where applicable)
Breast cancer survivor or relationship to a breast cancer survivor
We may request Personal Information, such as your user name or password, whenever you login to your account and may in limited circumstances ask you to provide credit card information and other personal information when purchasing goods that are offered for sale on our Sites or when making a donation online.
We reserve the right to request any additional information necessary to establish and maintain your account. Generally, our uses of Personal Information collected online include, without limitation, responding to your inquiry about volunteering time to Komen, enabling you to make a donation, purchasing a product from the Sites, or providing information, such as sending marketing communications and newsletters.
Komen will retain your Personal Information for fulfillment of the intended purposes for which such Personal Information is collected.
Komen will establish minimum and maximum retention periods based upon the type of information collected (i.e., sensitivity), the intended purposes and as otherwise may be legally required.
Personal Information shall NOT include any personal information posted or sent by or to you in any public forum (such as a message board) or a personal home page (if any) on the Sites.
Participation in these public forums and Komen fundraising initiatives requires the public release and dissemination of such information, and thus Komen cannot commit to treating such information confidentially in the same manner that other personal information will be treated under this Privacy Policy.
Participation in these programs is voluntary and thus your consent to certain terms is required before participation is allowed.
Aggregate Information Collected Automatically
When you visit the Sites, we automatically collect Aggregate Information about your visit. We can tell the type of computer, browser, and web service that you are using. We also know the date, time, and pages that you visit. Collecting this information helps us design the Sites to enhance your experience while on our Sites.
Komen also may use Aggregate Information for internal purposes, such as tracking demographic data and providing targeted content to make the Sites more useful to our visitors. The gathering of this Aggregate Information may be accomplished by the use of cookies or web beacons by Komen and its third party service providers
In particular, Komen will collect an IP Address from all visitors to the Sites. An IP Address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. Komen may share Aggregate Information with its research grant recipients, content providers, sponsors, service providers or other third parties to advance the goals of research, education, dissemination or information and otherwise in fulfillment of the Promise. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Sites, analyze trends, track users’ movement on the Sites, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the Sites, and deliver customized, personalized content.
IP addresses, however, are not linked to Personal Information.
Komen also may use a unique assigned number located with the Sites’ URL to determine the web site from which you navigated to get to the Sites. While this number may not be apparent to you, it does not contain your Personal Information.
Does Komen use COOKIES, OTHER TECHNOLOGIES or THIRD PARTIES to INDIRECTLY collect information on the Sites?
The Sites may use cookies to enhance your experience while using the Sites. Cookies are pieces of information that some websites transfer to the computer that is browsing that site and are used for record-keeping purposes at many websites. Use of cookies makes web-surfing easier by performing certain functions such as saving your passwords, your personal preferences regarding your use of the particular website and to make sure you do not see the same ad repeatedly. Many consider the use of cookies to be an industry standard.
Your browser is probably set to accept cookies. However, if you would prefer not to receive cookies, you can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies. If you choose to have your browser refuse cookies, it is possible that some areas of our Sites will not function properly when you view them.
The Sites also may use other technologies to track the specific pages viewed by visitors on the Sites or to target specific content that might be of interest to you. These technologies help us to understand how visitors use the Sites. However, you will have the option to opt out (or opt on if applicable law requires) of receiving such targeted content on those pages of our Sites where this technology is used.
Does Komen SHARE the information that I have provided or that has been collected?
Komen may need to share Personal Information with third parties in limited circumstances. For example, we may release Personal Information to third parties to perform services such as advising you of our upcoming events, products, volunteer opportunities, fundraising and partner-related product opportunities benefiting Komen, breast health/breast cancer information or processing credit card payments or hosting the Sites (and/or features available on the Sites). However, such third parties are obligated to maintain the confidentiality of Personal Information and are not authorized to use Personal Information for any purpose other than providing those services.
From time to time, we may be required to provide Personal Information or Aggregate Information in response to a valid court order, subpoena, government investigation, or as otherwise required by law, or if we reasonably believe that you have committed unlawful acts or acts that may endanger the health or safety of another user or the general public. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we, in good faith, believe to be unlawful. We may release certain personal information when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property, and safety of others and ourselves.
We also reserve the right to share, assign or transfer your Personal information to Komen Headquarters and its affiliates, or any successor in interest to our organization by merger, reorganization, or operation of law.
In addition, Komen may make your name and postal address available to other non-profit organizations whose services or activities may be of interest to you.
Do I have CHOICES regarding how my Personal Information is used?
Komen may make your name and postal address available to other nonprofit organizations whose services or activities may be of interest to you. If you would like to opt out of having Komen share your name and postal address with those organizations, please click here: Opt Out.
Komen has made available the public forums on the Sites so that you may have an opportunity to interact with other Site visitors in order to share knowledge and news or participate in fundraising events benefiting Komen.
Since participation in such forums is voluntary, you control what personal information may be disclosed to others.
In order to avoid your email address or other personal information from being gathered and used by others for unsolicited, inappropriate or harmful purposes, Komen advises that you should be cautious about posting your email address or phone number or other personal information to newsgroups, blogs, message boards, or other
public forums.
In addition, access to Personal Information contained in your account is protected by use of a password so keep your password private and secure.
How can I UPDATE or CHANGE my information?
Komen wants your account (including without limitation, your Personal Information and preferences) to be accurate and complete. To update or change your Personal Information, visit our user login page and log on to your own account. You can update your Personal Information after logging in to your account.
How does Komen SECURE my personal information?
Komen maintains commercially reasonable safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of the Personal Information provided by you. Such security safeguards are intended to be appropriate to the sensitivity of the Personal Information collected. To the extent Komen transfers any Personal Information to third-parties, Komen will use commercially reasonable efforts to assure that such third-parties to whom it may transfer any Personal Information have knowledge of this Privacy Policy and provide sufficient protection of such Personal Information. In particular, Komen requires that a secure session be established using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) and Secure Electronic Transaction (SET) protocol when you submit Personal Information to us through your use of the Sites to establish an account, use the shopping cart, input credit card or debit card information for payment, and access certain web pages on the Sites.
Additionally, Komen utilizes digital certificates issued by an established signer of digital certificates.
Komen is committed to properly securing the Personal Information collected online. To help us accomplish this, we take the following steps:
We employ internal access controls to ensure that the only people who see your information are those with a need to do so to perform their official duties.
We train relevant personnel on our privacy and security measures.
We physically secure the areas where we hold hard copies of the information that we collect online.
We regularly back up the information that we collect online to insure against loss.
We use technical controls to secure the information that we collect online as appropriate, including but not limited to: Secure Socket Layer (SSL), encryption, firewalls, and password protections.
We periodically test our security procedures to ensure personnel and technical compliance.
Please note that Personal Information stored on the Sites will be collected, stored and processed in the United States of America.
By this Privacy Policy, Komen has intended to abide by the safe harbor framework as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of data from the European Union and the PIPEDA regarding the collection, use and retention of data from Canada.
Does Komen collect information from CHILDREN?
Since the Sites are not designed specifically for children, Komen does not intentionally collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13.
If we discover that we have inadvertently collected Personal Information from a person under the age of 13, we will automatically delete it.
If I give Komen the name and email address of my family or friends, how is that information used?
If you elect to use any features of the Sites (such as “Tell A Friend”) to inform a friend about the Sites or solicit donations or pledges or otherwise communicate, Komen may ask for your friend’s name and email address.
The Sites may automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the Sites or otherwise provide the information requested by you.
Komen will store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.
Your friend may contact Komen to request the removal of this information from our databases.
Whom can I CONTACT if I have questions or concerns about the Privacy Policy?
Komen has designated our Privacy Manager who can be contacted at the Komen contact address listed at the end of this Privacy Policy. Our Privacy Manager is accountable for Komen’s online compliance with this Privacy Policy. If you have questions about our Privacy Policy or if you have a claim concerning our compliance with this Privacy Policy, you can e-mail our Privacy Manager at gpeck@komennyc.org.
Please provide a description of your claims or questions in sufficient detail so as to permit our Privacy Manager to investigate your claims or questions fully and contact you.
It is our intent to make available to you through our Privacy Manager specific information about this Privacy Policy and our management of your Personal Information as may be required by applicable law.
Will this Privacy Policy CHANGE?
Since the Sites will continue to implement new technologies and improve the services and features, this Privacy Policy is subject to change. If there are changes or additions to this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes here or in other formats that we deem acceptable, so that you will always know what information we collect online, how we use it and what choices you have.
What constitutes my acceptance of this Privacy Policy?
By using the Sites, you expressly consent to the use and disclosure of information as described in this Privacy Policy.
Your continued use of the Sites after the effective date of any modification to the Privacy Policy will be deemed to be your agreement to the changed terms.
You agree to review the Privacy Policy each time you use the Sites so that you are aware of such modifications.
How does Komen protect the information that I may provide by telephone or regular mail or in person?
Komen implements these same policies and procedures to protect the privacy of any Personal Information voluntarily submitted by you to Komen via telephone or regular mail or in person.
Our Privacy Manager also is accountable for Komen’s off-line compliance with this Privacy Policy.
If you have any questions about any Personal Information provided by one of these off-line methods, you may check your on-line account or otherwise contact our Privacy Manager by email, regular mail or telephone at the contact address listed in this Privacy Policy.
Edited: November 2016
Go to Top
